Northern Soul is a music, drama film directed by Elaine Constantine.
Set in 1974, an authentic and uplifting tale of two friends whose horizons
are opened up by the discovery of black American soul music.
John Clark, played by Elliot James Langridge.
Matt, played by Josh Whitehouse.
Angela, played by Antonia Thomas.
Mr. Banks, played by Steve Coogan.
Ray Henderson, played by James Lance.
Paul, played by Ashley Taylor Dawson.
Northern Soul is a 2014 British historical film directed by Elaine Constantine.
It tells the story of two young Lancashire teenagers, Matt and John, whose lives are changed forever by the
discovery of African-American soul music and the dance culture that grew up around it in Britain.
The film was selected to be shown in the City to City
section of the 2015 Toronto Film Festival.
The film explores themes of 1970s, woman director, lancashire, soul music.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.